Valerii Olshevskyi

Kyiv, Ukraine | +1 860 348 3211 | linkedin.com/in/valerii-olshevskyi-b2a067287 | emeralddev92@gmail.com

Summary

Senior frontend developer with passion for crafting websites. Have 7+ years of experience in frontend development and 3+ in blockchain space. Specialized in MERN stack, Next, Nuxt and Svelte integrated in various blockchain networks, also backend development including node, laravel, Django with TDD methodology.

Experience

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER | C3 EXPERIENTIAL | 03/2022 - 07/2023

- Developed interactive learning game Rest APIs using Django, covering subjects like numbers relations, puzzles, foundational meths, CS foundamentals and science foundations
- Build serverless, microservice-architecture SaaS services using AWS API Gateway, AWS Lambda, AWS RDS, AWS Cognito, AWS Amplify, Python, Node, React, and Vue.
- · Created pipelines for CI/CD for web development from scratch using GitHub Actions, AWS CloudFormation, AWS, SAM CLI, and AWS Amplify.
- · Integrated third-party APIs such as Stripe, PayPal, Twilio, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, AWS SDK, Zoho API, Hubspot, SendGrid, MailGun, Mandrill, MailChimp, etc.
- · Collaborate to form firm view of quality metrics and expectations for the delivery, and work with these throughout the sprint
- · Work on POCs and cutting-edge features before they're integrated into the product

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER | CHIMPLIE | 06/2019 - 02/2022 | REMOTE

- Lead the small agile team of 6 members while design, developing and testing in-store order creation and management app using HTML, CSS, React, Javascript that meets accessibility and web browser standards for website
- · Created a Node.js notification server and frontend client that uses WebSockets to distribute notifications.
- · Applied ECMA Script 6 features to build JSX elements and functions in React components
- · Used React Hooks and Context API for effective state management in 60% of React projects
- · Focused on improving SEO, increased searching priority
- · Wrote the standardized components with the Storybook and wrote the unit testing with Jest.
- · Created the structure and web pages layout as per the user requirements with 100% client satisfaction.

BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER | ADORIASOFT | 11/2019 - 07/2021, REMOTE

- Took part in building Celsius network, a peer to peer lending network and a one stop solution for all crypto assets enable lending, borrowing and earning interest on deposited coins
- Took part in making Aidonic, social fundraising and digital aid distribution technology for humanitarian aid and development programs
- · Build NFT marketplace & P2E games, add token bridge functionality and contributed to Web3 projects

- Lead a team of Frontend, Backend and Smart Contract developers based on the concept of "Let's grow together"
- Developed software that helped customers to simulate loans which increased the loans by 10%

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | BRAINBEAN APPS | 05/2016 - 10/2019

- Implemented pixel perfect design with HTML5, CSS3, SASS, less and build 4+ web applications by using responsive UI elements via React concepts for smooth performance
- Experienced in working with Redux architecture using complex Object-Oriented concepts in improving the performance of the websites.
- Build highly responsive UI components using React and Redux, optimizing cross-browser compatibility across 12 major providers based on design.
- · Lead frontend team of 5 developers from 2018
- · Took part in the development of node modules that is used for company

Education

BCS | TARAS SHEVCHENKO UNIVERSITY OF KYIV

· Certificate for attending two days workshop on Machine learning

Skills & Abilities

LANGUAGE

· C/C++, Java, Javascript, Python, Solidity, Rust, C#, Go, Ruby, PHP, HTML, CSS

FRONTEND

· React/Next, Vue/Nuxt, Angular, Javascript, Typescript, CSS, TailwindCSS, MaterialUI, Svelte, RestAPI

BACKEND

· Express, Nest, Laravel, Django, Flask, Fast API, ASP.NET, Spring Boot, Golang, ROR, REST API, GraphQL

DATABASE

· MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle, SQLite, Redis, Firebase

BLOCKCHAIN

· Solidity, Truffle, Hardhat, Rust, NFT Marketplace, P2E, Betting, Farming, DEX, DeFi, DAO, Consensus protocols, Layer2 Concepts, Ethereum, Binance Smart Chain, Solana, Polygon

OTHERS

· Jira, Azure, Trello, AWS, Google cloud platform, Microsoft Azure, Git, GitLab, Butbucket, Docker, Ngnix, Heroku, Netlify, Vercel, CI/CD, Jest, Mocha, Jasmin, Cypress, Selenium, Scrum, Kanban, Jenkins, Kubernate